

Aleksandr B

LANGUAGES

English - C1

Cloud Developer (DevOps)

WHO AM I?

15+ years of experience in development, network, system administration, DevOps. Fluency in coding and high traffic / high availability system architecture. Experience in working with distributed teams, good communication skills. Ability to quickly learn new technologies and practices. Organizational and time management skills. Analytical and problem-solving skills. Speak English with full professional proficiency and higher. Like to solve complex problems. I'm interested in programming, system administration, architecture, and clouds.

SKILLS

Linux Kubernetes	HELM	ArgoCD	Docker	Azure	AWS	GitOps	Terraforn	n An	sible
ELK Prometheus	Grafana	MySQL	Git	JavaScript	Mongol	DB Rat	obitMQ	Ruby	Python

EDUCATION

EXPERIENCE

2020 — 2023 Senior DevOps Engineer

Contractor

Internal platform based on Kubernetes for British fintech company product. - Automating infrastructure deployment to Azure via Terraform and various services to Kubernetes via Helm ArgoCD. - Made integration of 3-rd party services like Kafka, Cassandra with HashiCorp Vault in Kubernetes. - Product Migration to Kubernetes. - DevOps consultation. - Managing infrastructure for Crypto company. - Migrating infra to Terraform IaC. Upgrading Kubernetes. Integrating Elastic Cloud on Kubernetes (ECK).

AWS	HELM	Terraform	Kubernetes	Azure	ArgoCD
-----	------	-----------	------------	-------	--------

2019 — 2020 Senior DevOps Infrastructure Engineer

Tinkoff

Was supporting DevOps services. - Setting up CI/CD. - Solving problems in service and infrastructure. - Migrating services to Kubernetes.

CI/CD Kubernetes

2016 — 2019 Lead DevOps Engineer

Cloudike Korea

Product: Dropbox-like Enterprise cloud storage system. Was supporting CI/CD. - planning specifications, - deploying product to Clouds and on-premise environments, - debugging python code. - Solved difficult bugs. - Optimized service performance, MongoDB queries, and indexes. - Analyze and optimize cloud infrastructure costs. - Migrated whole product services to Docker.

CI/CD Docker MongoDB

2009 — 2016 NN.RU

Lead System Administrator

Lead system administration of High Load web service. Several data centers, multiple internet channels plus IX. - Was solving performance and stability problems. - Analyze and optimize the performance of web and SQL servers and SQL queries, make hardware specifications, and plan infrastructure. - Integrated object storage for content storage. - Developed web server for web counter system on Node.js. - Provided infrastructure for 3x product growth. - Increased service stability. Decreased page load time. - Automated development environment management via Ansible and LXC.

SQL Node.js

2006 — 2009 **NOC Engineer**

ER-Telecom

Internet Service Provider. Was administering the core and backbone network. Traffic Engineering. QOS. Setup monitoring (Nagios, Zabbix, Cacti). Solving network problems. Made network discovery service based on CDP and FDB.

Zabbix Cacti Nagios